Medbh McGuckian papers, 1964-2006
Emory University
- Writings by Medbh McGuckian, Series 2; Boxes 16-30, OP 1-3
  - Poetry, Subseries 2.1; Box 16 - Box 25: Folder 45; OP 1-3
    - "Apple Flesh," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - "Balakhana," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - "The Bird Auction," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - "The Blue She Brings With Her," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - "Blue Sky Rain," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 56)
    - "Blue Vase," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 57)
    - "Coleridge," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - "A Conversation Set to Flowers," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 59)
    - "Death of a Ceiling," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - "A Dream in Three Colours," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - "The Dream Language of Fergus," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - "First Letters from a Steamer," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - "For a Young Matron," MS and TS [variant title: "L-[?] Bark, June '85"] (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - "Four O' Clock, Summer Street," MS [variant title: "Four O' Clock On Summer Street"] (Box 17, Folder 65)
    - "Frost in Beaconsfield," MS (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - "Girls in the Plural," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 67)
    - "Grainne's Sleep Song," MS and TS (Box 17, Folder 68)
    - "Harem Trousers," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "Head of a Woman," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Lighthouse With Dead Leaves," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Little House, Big House," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Mazurka," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Minus 18 Street," MS (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "My Brown Guest," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Not Pleasing Mama," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "On Ballycastle Beach," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "On Not Being Listened To," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "Querencia," MS [See also Subseries 2.1, On Ballycastle Beach, "Four O' Clock, Summer Street," MS] (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "Scenes From a Brothel," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "Sea or Sky?," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "The Sky Marshal," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - "Sleep School," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - "Staying in a Better Hotel," MS and TS [variant titles: "A Rest in a Better Hotel" and "Six Weeks in a Better Hotel"] [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Mad River," and "Something Like a Wind," MS] (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - "Through the Round Window," MS (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "The Time Before You," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "To a Cuckoo at Coolanlough," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "To the Oak-Leaf Camps," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "What Does Early Mean?," MS, TS, and proof [variant title: "But What Does Early Mean?"] (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - "Woman with a Blue-Ringed Bowl," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - "Yeastlight," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - "Ylang-Ylang," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - On Ballycastle Beach, Corrected title page proof (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - On Ballycastle Beach, Typescripts (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - On Ballycastle Beach, Proof with corrections (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Two Women, Two Shores (1989) [See also Subseries 2.5, Notebooks]
    - "Before the Wedding," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - "Blue Farm," TS (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - "Calling Canada," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - "Children of the Mist," MS, TS, and proof (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - "Christmas Eve," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Two Women, Two Shores, "Children of the Mist," proof] (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - "The Chrysanthemum Party," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Pain Tells You What to Wear," MS] (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - "The Colouring Book," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - "The 'Esther Sleepe'," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Felicia's Café," MS] (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - "The Flower Clock," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - "The Frame," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Artemesia," TS] (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - "The Last Day of Pisces," TS (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - "Magazines," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Underground," MS] (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - "The Milk Cap," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Lucina," TS] (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - "The Missing Tennis Suit," MS and TS [variant title: "The Tennis Suit"] [See also Subseries 2.1: Two Women, Two Shores, "Children of the Mist," proof] (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - "Mrs. Orchard," MS and proof (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - "Never," MS (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - "Painting Over," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - "Paris," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Miss Twelves," MS] (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - "The Parsonage," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - "The Presence," MS, TS, and proof (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - "The Sudarium," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Lime Trees in Winter, Retouched," MS] (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - "The Throne," MS (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - "Too Much Yellow," MS and TS (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Two Women, Two Shores, TS (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Marconi's Cottage (1991) [See also Subseries 2.5, Notebooks]
    - "The After-Thinker," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Almond," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Amsterdam Avenue," MS (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "The Book Room," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Branches," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "Breaking the Blue," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "Brothers and Uncles," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "The Carrying Ring," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "Charlotte's Delivery," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "The Cloth Mother," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Clotho," MS, TS, and proof [variant titles: "Clothes" and "Clothos"] (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "The Cutting-Out Room," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "Dear Rain," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Two Women, Two Shores, "Mrs. Orchard," proof] (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "A Different Same," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Aphrodisiac," proof] (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "Dormer Window," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "Earth Weather," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Marconi's Cottage, "Clotho," proof] (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - "East of Mozart," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - "Echo Poem," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - "Flowered Sitting Room," MS and TS [variant title: "Sitting Room"] (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - "From the First Underworld," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - "Gigot Sleeves," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - "In the Rainshadow," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - "The Invalid's Echo," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - "Journal Intime," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "The Keeper Ring," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - "Lac de Galance," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - "The Liontamer," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - "The Man with Two Women," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - "Marconi's Cottage," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - "The Most Emily of All," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - "No Streets, No Numbers," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - "On Her Second Birthday," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - "Open Rose," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Marconi's Cottage, "Charlotte's Delivery," MS] (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - "Oval of a Girl," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - "The Partner's Desk," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - "Red Armchair," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - "Road 32, Roof 12-23, Grass 23," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - "The Rosary Dress," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - "Shaferi," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - "She Which Is Not, He Which Is," MS (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - "Sky in Narrow Streets," MS and TS [variant titles: "Nowhere," "To Wake the Forest"] (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - "Sky-Writing," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - "A Small Piece of Wood," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - "The Snow Speaker," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - "Springwater," TS (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - "Storm Flap," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - "The Sun-Moon Child," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - "Swallow's Wood, Glenshesk," MS (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - "Teraphim," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - "Time-Words," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - "To Call Paula Paul," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - "Turning the Moon into a Verb," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Aphrodisiac," proof] (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - "The Unplayed Rosalind," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - "Venus and the Sea," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - "Vibratory Description," MS (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - "View Without a Room," MS (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - "Visiting Rainer Maria," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - "The War Ending," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Marconi's Cottage, "Venus and the Sea," MS] (Box 19, Folder 58)
    - "The Watch Fire," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - Captain Lavender (1994) [See also Subseries 2.5, Notebooks]
    - "The Aisling Hat," MS (Box 19, Folder 60)
    - "The Albert Chain," MS and TS (Box 19, Folder 61)
    - "The Appropriate Moment," MS and TS [includes"Faith," "Et Animum Dimittit," "Astral Picture," and "Ignotas in Artes"] (Box 19, Folder 62)
    - "Between the 8 and the 9," MS (Box 19, Folder 63)
    - "Black Virgin," MS, TS, and proof (Box 19, Folder 64)
    - "Captain Lavender," MS (Box 19, Folder 65)
    - "Ceramic and Wood for Bronze," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "The Colour Shop," TS (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Constable's 'Haywain,'" MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Credenza," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "Cupboard with Painted Ship," MS (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "Dante's Own Day," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Dividing the Political Temperature," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Captain Lavender, "Black Virgin," proof] (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Drawing in Red Chalk at a Death Sale," MS and TS [variant title: "Drawing in Red Chalk"] (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - "Elegy for an Irish Speaker," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - "Field Heart," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "The Finder has Become the Seeker," MS and TS [variant title: "The Seeker has Become the Finder"] (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "Flirting with Saviours," TS (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - "For the Wind Millionaire," MS (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - "Lines for Thanksgiving," TS (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - "The Nearness of the Grape Arbour to the Fruit Cellar," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "The Over Mother," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - "Porcelain Bells," MS and TS [includes "Candles at Three Thirty," "Story Between Two Notes," "Speaking Into the Candles"] (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - "The Radio Traitor," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - "Reverse Cinderella," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - "The Silkwinder," MS (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - "Skull-light," MS (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - "Still Life of Eggs," TS (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - "Timed Chess," MS (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - "Unused Water," MS (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - "The Wake Sofa," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - "The War Degree," MS (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - "Waxwing Winter," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - "White Windsor Soap," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Captain Lavender, "Black Virgin," Proof] (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Selected Poems (1997)
    - Cover art proofs (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Shelmalier (1998) [See also Subseries 2.5, Notebooks]
    - "Altar Girl," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - "Arbalests and Mangonels," TS (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - "The Birthday of Monday," TS (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - "A Blessing of Weapons," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - "The Blood Changer," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - "Blue Doctrine," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - "The Brownstone Bride," TS (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - "The Building of the 'Hebe,'" TS (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - "Cancelleresca Bastarda," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - "Captain Heaven," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - "Circle With Full Stop," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - "Cleaning Out the Workhouse," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - "Columbarium," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - "Cornet Love," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - "Creggan Churchyard," TS (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - "Dream in a Train," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - "The Feastday of Peace," TS (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - "The Feminine Christs," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - "The Field of Nonduality," TS (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - "Film-Still," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - "Foliage Ceiling Rose," TS (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - "Fox's Skin," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - "From the Weather-Woman," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - "Good Friday, 1995," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - "Habeas Corpus," TS (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - "Home Daughter," MS, TS, and proof (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - "Impressionist House," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - "Killing the Muse," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 57)
    - "La Bien Cercada; The Well-Walled," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 58)
    - "Lake in Middle Shadow," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 59)
    - "The Latissimus Station," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 60)
    - "A Light Form of War," TS (Box 20, Folder 61)
    - "Man Dressed as a Skeleton," TS (Box 20, Folder 62)
    - "Man of War Bird," TS (Box 20, Folder 63)
    - "Man with Crossed Arms," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 64)
    - "Man with Pool Furniture," MS and TS [variant title: "Man with Open Sleeves"] (Box 20, Folder 65)
    - "Mantilla," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 66)
    - "Mass Read by Night in the Open Air," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 67)
    - "Month Without an R," TS [See also Subseries 2.1: Drawing Ballerinas, "The Colony Room," MS] (Box 20, Folder 68)
    - "More Than a Letter," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 69)
    - "Pass Christian," TS (Box 20, Folder 70)
    - "Plague Song," MS, TS, and proof (Box 20, Folder 71)
    - "The Potter," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 72)
    - "Praying Male Figurine," TS (Box 20, Folder 73)
    - "Pulsus Paradoxus," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 74)
    - "Rathlin Road," TS (Box 20, Folder 75)
    - "The Rose-Trellis," TS (Box 20, Folder 76)
    - "Script for an Unchanging Voice," TS (Box 20, Folder 77)
    - "Self-Portrait in the Act of Painting a Self-Portrait," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 78)
    - "Sentinelle Perdue," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Shelmalier, "Impressionist House"] (Box 20, Folder 79)
    - "The Shadow Lord," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 80)
    - "The Shadow Prize," TS (Box 20, Folder 81)
    - "Shannon's Recovery," TS (Box 20, Folder 82)
    - "The She-Eagles," TS (Box 20, Folder 83)
    - "Shelmalier," MS and TS [variant title: "Mathematically, At Least a Door"] (Box 20, Folder 84)
    - "Shoulder-Length, Caged Parrot Earrings," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 85)
    - "The Sickness of the Cloth," MS and TS (Box 20, Folder 86)
    - "Sky Portrait," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "Society of the Bomb," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "The Sofa in the Window With the Trees Outside," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - "The Sound Healer," TS (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "The Spirit Dolls," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - "Standing Army," TS (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "Stone Orchard," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "Stone with Potent Figure," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "Summer of a Dormouse," [See Subseries 2.1, Shelmalier, "Arbalests and Mangonels," TS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Tamarind Tree," TS (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "Tectiform," TS (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "The Temple of Janus," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Their Word for Harvest Suffering," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Shelmalier, "Plague Song," Proof] (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "The Third Chessplayer," TS (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "The Tree Cloud," TS (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Using the Cushion," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "War Masquerading as Love," [See Subseries 2.1, Shelmalier, "Arbalests and Mangonels," TS (Box -, Folder -)
    - "What the Month Brings," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - "White Magpie," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - "The Word-Thrower," TS (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - "The Would-be Winter," TS (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Drawing Ballerinas (2001) [See also Subseries 2.5, Notebooks]
    - "Act of Settlement," MS (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - "After the Honeysuckle," MS (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - "At Mullaghmore," MS [See also Subseries 2.1: Marconi's Cottage, "The Carrying Ring," MS] (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - "A Ballet Called Culloden," MS (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - "Black Raven on Cream-Coloured Background," MS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Face of the Earth, "The Change Worshipper," MS] (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - "Closed Eye Song," MS (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - "The Colony Room," MS (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - "Copperheads," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - "The Dead are More Alive," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - "The Disinternment," MS (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - "Drawing Ballerinas," MS (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - "The Frost Fair," MS (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - "Gaeltacht na Fuiseoige," MS (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - "Hazel Lavery, The Green Coat, 1926," MS (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - "Jesus of the Evening," TS (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - "Manteo," Notes, MS (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - "Martyrdom-de-Luxe," MS (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - "The Mickey-Mouse Gas Mask," MS (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - "The Miniver," TS (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - "Monody for Aghas," MS [variant title: "Aghas-A Monody"] (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - "Moonflowers," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - "The Moses Room," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Marconi's Cottage, "View Without a Room," MS] (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - "Oration," MS (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - "The Red Trial," MS [variant title: "The Red Trail"] (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - "Saxon Slave Clock," MS (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - "The Swan Trap," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Notes, MS (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Drawing Ballerinas, proof (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - The Face of the Earth (2002) [See also Subseries 2.5, Notebooks]
    - "The Back Causeway," TS (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - "The Brood-bird," TS (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - "The Change Worshipper," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Drawing Ballerinas, "Manteo," Notes, MS] (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - "The Dance Garden," MS (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - "Displaced to the Blue," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - "The Face of the Earth," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 53)
    - "Field Character," TS (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - "The Fortified Song of Flowers," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 55)
    - "The Gas Curtain," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 56)
    - "Glove-Silver," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 57)
    - "High Altitude Lavender," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 58)
    - "House with Its Own Island," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Drawing Ballerinas, "Manteo," Notes, MS] (Box 21, Folder 59)
    - "Image of Migratory Cranes," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 60)
    - "The Journey Present," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 61)
    - "Love-Spot," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 62)
    - "Making Your Own Eclipse," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 63)
    - "Melisma," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 64)
    - "The Moon-Spirit," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 65)
    - "Mourning Engagement Ring," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 66)
    - "Navicella," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 67)
    - "The Piano Silker," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 68)
    - "The Presence of Her Absence," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 69)
    - "Ramoan Parish Bulletin," TS (Box 21, Folder 70)
    - "Reading the Earthquake," TS [variant title: "Reading the Fire"] [See also Subseries 2.1, Drawing Ballerinas, "Hazel Lavery, The Green Coat, 1926," MS, and Subseries 2.1, The Face of the Earth, "Making Your Own Eclipse," MS] (Box 21, Folder 71)
    - "Revival of Gathered Scents," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 72)
    - "Roseweather," TS (Box 21, Folder 73)
    - "She is in the Past, She has this Grace," MS (Box 21, Folder 74)
    - "Sky Farmer," TS (Box 21, Folder 75)
    - "Sleeping with the Sea," MS and TS [variant title: "Pages of Stone"] (Box 21, Folder 76)
    - "Small View of Spire and River," TS (Box 21, Folder 77)
    - "Soeur de Lait," MS (Box 21, Folder 78)
    - "Something Called Sleep," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 79)
    - "Speranza," TS (Box 21, Folder 80)
    - "Spoiled Muse," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Had I a Thousand Lives, "Locust in the Cemetery," MS] (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - "Studies of Her Right Breast," TS (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - "Temple-sleep," TS (Box 21, Folder 83)
    - "This Ember Week," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 84)
    - "Understudying Envy," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 85)
    - "Valentine Not To Be Opened," MS and TS (Box 21, Folder 86)
    - "Viewing Neptune through a Glass Telescope," TS (Box 21a, Folder 1)
    - "The Water Guardian," TS (Box 21a, Folder 2)
    - "The Worship of the Plough," MS and TS (Box 21a, Folder 3)
    - The Soldiers of Year II (2002)
    - "Birthday Composition of Horses," Notes, MS (Box 21a, Folder 4)
    - "English as a Foreign Language," MS and TS (Box 21a, Folder 5)
    - "Fourteenth Century Hours of the Virgin," TS (Box 21a, Folder 6)
    - "Gander Month," MS (Box 21a, Folder 7)
    - "The Gregory Quarter-Acre Clause," proof and MS (with fax from Bill Coleman) (Box 21a, Folder 8)
    - "The Half-Marriage," TS (Box 21a, Folder 9)
    - "Hessian, Linen, Silk," MS (Box 21a, Folder 10)
    - "An Invalid in War," MS (Box 21a, Folder 11)
    - "Mating with the Well," TS [See Subseries 2.1: Shelmalier, "The Tamarind Tree," TS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Modern Proserpine," TS (Box 21a, Folder 12)
    - "The Muse Hater's Small Green Passion," MS and TS (Box 21a, Folder 13)
    - "Operation Market Garden," MS and TS (Box 21a, Folder 14)
    - "Pincushion with Beaded Cross," MS (Box 21a, Folder 15)
    - "A Poem for St. Patrick's Day," MS (Box 21a, Folder 16)
    - "Ring Size M ½," MS (Box 21a, Folder 17)
    - "The Soldiers of Year II," MS (Box 21a, Folder 18)
    - "Soliloquy to a Cloud," MS (Box 21a, Folder 19)
    - "Thinking of the Whole Island," MS (Box 21a, Folder 20)
    - "Three Rings, Six Graves," MS (Box 21a, Folder 21)
    - "Thunder: Perfect Mind," MS [See also Subseries 2.1, Had I a Thousand Lives, "Photograph of a Passerine in Song," MS] (Box 21a, Folder 22)
    - "To Make Two Bridges Necessary," MS (Box 21a, Folder 23)
    - "To My Disordered Muse" [See Subseries 2.1, Drawing Ballerinas, "Hazel Lavery, The Green Coat, 1926," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "To Such a Hermes," Notes, MS (Box 21a, Folder 24)
    - Table of Contents, MS (Box 21a, Folder 25)
    - Had I a Thousand Lives (2003)
    - "Against Cityness," MS (Box 21a, Folder 26)
    - "Asking for the Alphabet Back," Proof [See Subseries 2.1: Shelmalier, "Plague Song"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Bedroom with Chrysanthemums," MS (Box 21a, Folder 27)
    - "Blue Kasina," MS (Box 21a, Folder 28)
    - "The Chamomile Lawn," MS (Box 21a, Folder 29)
    - "The Chimney Boys," MS (Box 21a, Folder 30)
    - "Corduroy Road," MS (Box 21a, Folder 31)
    - "The Deadest Deaths Are the Best," MS [variant title: "Self-Portrait in a Convex Mirror"] (Box 21a, Folder 32)
    - "A Deserted Landing-Stage on the Rhine," MS (Box 21a, Folder 33)
    - "Hearing the Weather Fall," MS (Box 21a, Folder 34)
    - "Jeszcze Polska," MS (Box 21a, Folder 35)
    - "Locust in the Cemetery," MS (Box 21a, Folder 36)
    - "Low Low Sunday," MS (Box 21a, Folder 37)
    - "The Mirror Game," MS (Box 21a, Folder 38)
    - "Not Yielding to the Will of Yellow," MS (Box 21a, Folder 39)
    - "Petit Bleu," MS (Box 21a, Folder 40)
    - "Photograph of a Passerine in Song," MS (Box 21a, Folder 41)
    - "Pilgrimage to Poland," MS (Box 21a, Folder 42)
    - "Porzana, Porzana," TS (Box 21a, Folder 43)
    - "The Pyx Sleeper," MS (Box 21a, Folder 44)